[music]
Hey, what's up guys? Welcome back to the
Holy Happy Hour. Today we will be
watching a video of one of my favorite
minds on the internet, which is Alex
Okconor. He's a popular atheist, maybe
agnostic. I I don't know what he would
claim to be, but he is someone that is
truly logically trying to connect the
dots. And because they don't connect, he
currently claims that Christianity is
not true, but there have been apparently
some rumors that there have been some
like breakthroughs lately. But yeah, but
I want I want to specifically look at
this video today because there are a lot
of people like him that have these
conversations with people like I believe
it's the Nectals or the Nectal that I
just truly don't think that the answers
and the conversation is handled the best
way. But also, I don't think that the
questions and the analogies being thrown
out are the best either. I think that
this entire video, this reaction
actually has one simple answer to it,
but we're going to watch the whole
thing. It's about 9 minutes. It's pretty
short and we are going to check out his
arguments and then try to give our own
fe like take on it and then I would love
to hear your guys' take in the comment
section as well whether you agree with
the nectals or if you agree with kind of
what I'm saying which is honestly more
so based on a very very little research
and stuff to it but more so just my
Catholic logical thinking and uh yeah
this is this video is to made to to
hopefully start a great conversation and
to grow in my faith but I I I think it's
going to be be an awesome video,
especially during this season. We are in
the first week of Advent. I'm actually
currently recording this on the first
Sunday of Advent. So, I hope you guys
are enjoying this season. And this
season is just about waiting for the
Savior to be born. And what's super cool
about this is that it's waiting on
something to celebrate, something that
has happened that we know is going to
happen. and we get this amazing awesome
opportunity to celebrate the the birth
of Jesus Christ on on December 25th. But
it's also a great time to prepare
ourselves for the second coming of
Jesus, to prepare ourselves for the end
of our lives, knowing that we never know
when it's going to happen and that we
should always be prepared. I love when
Jesus goes off to pray and he's there
for an hour and then he turns back he
comes back and his his disciples are
sleeping and he literally asks him was
you couldn't stay awake for even an hour
and I love that verse because it is just
a great message of
constantly being prepared never knowing
when your name's going to get called
knowing when Jesus is going to call you
home when you're going to be yeah put in
a situation where you need to be
prepared for that judgment day and
that's exactly what this video is about
they're talking about this going to hell
versus not going to hell, unrepented,
dying versus repenting first and then
dying. And I I just think some of the
answers in here are a little silly. And
I think some of the answers are honestly
a very strong thing to say. And I think
that's really dangerous to do is to make
such a bold statement that Cliff makes
about halfway through the video. But
we're going to check out the video
today. Again, you guys comment below.
Make sure you guys like and subscribe to
support the channel. and we are going to
jump right into it cuz I know that's
what you guys are here for. So, let's
share our screen and we're going to get
right into
Alex Okconor's video.
Welcomed into the kingdom of God until
you die.
It's like,
"Oh, but Lord, I died yesterday." "Oh,
well, you're dead. Oh, well, then the
game's up. Tough luck,
right? You you'll be forgiven of
anything you like. But if you die
unrepentant and you're not making it
into the kingdom of God, this this
unconditional
forgiveness on grounds of repentance
seems to sort of time out at the point
of death. Now death is quite significant
but
>> okay so I want to go and stop it there
because he does go on actually a very
long kind of all around the place and he
even acknowledges it but he he's making
this point of dying without repenting
and wondering why would forgiveness stop
then and there like why why wouldn't it
extend beyond death
and my question would be why should it
extend beyond death we don't deserve for
it to extend during our lifetime him.
This is a free gift given to us by God.
And it's something that he sent his son
to actually bridge the gap of this chasm
that we created on the fall. And we now
have the opportunity to accept Jesus, to
follow Jesus, to live the way that the
um that Jesus taught the apostles and
told them to teach us the traditions and
the writings. We we have this way to
worship and and ways to confess our
sins. We have all these things. He's
given us the playbook. He's given us a
church, a magisterium, a pope.
Obviously, this from the Catholic point
point of view, but even just from a
Christian point of view, he gave us the
Bible. That's something that we can go
to, we can learn from, and we can truly
understand how we should be living this
life. And [snorts] that anything living
like an unrepented way and then dying
would be actively choosing not to go
there. Now, you can go into the whole
conversation of like the the ignorant
that that dies that never ever heard of
Jesus, was never presented the gospel,
never got the chance to even repent of
their sins because they didn't know what
sins were. And that's just like a whole
another question. But I want to go and
stop and give those comments because I I
think this is kind of a a flawed
question and it's almost like just needs
to be answered with a question. But he's
going to go on for a little bit longer.
Why would it be that someone who died
yesterday confronted with you know
whatever it might be eternal torment
eternal separation from God and decides
actually I don't [snorts] know about
this at least in a lot of traditional
Christian teachings it's too late for
them why why doesn't this sort of un
this um
unadulterated willingness to forgive
extend beyond the grave
>> which means whoever tells you that it
doesn't matter how you live. He's
smoking something I don't want to smoke.
Because what Jesus points out is it
matters desperately how you live. It
matters desperately what decisions you
make in life because the decisions that
you make in this life have eternal
ramification. Now, first of all, I want
to say if I'm not wrong that Cliff very
often kind of preaches this sole fed,
but exactly what he said right there was
basically the way you live and the works
that you do are very much matter. And
this is like the whole point of this
faith without works is dead. And so when
we're saved by faith alone, like we're
saved by our faith in Jesus, but but
faith without works, without the the the
the living out the life of a disciple,
that kind of works is dead. So faith
without works is dead. And this is where
this this massive just absolute
miscommunication of people [snorts] not
understanding that Catholics believe
that yes, that we are saved because of
of everything Jesus did, that we
ourselves cannot do anything to earn our
way into heaven. But Jesus did give us
rules and he gave us ways to worship and
ways to again confess our sins and ways
to pray. He gave us specific things to
do and ways um to to live our lives so
that we can be in full communion with
him. He also gave us a lot of things not
to do as well. And so it is that the
things we do and the things we don't do,
the things we engage in, the things we
don't engage in are super super
important. So, what he's saying is true.
Um, now I don't really think it answered
the question. I like I think it was a
really silly answer um to what he just
said, but let's keep let's keep going
here what else he has to say.
>> But why does that generosity end at
death? I mean, as Christians, you
believe that that you you you're not
really a body. You have a body, right?
You are you're a soul. There's an
immaterial component to you. You are
you. And when you die and your body
decomposes, there will still be a you
that will exist. So, we'll get a new
body, whatever your esquetology is.
Fine.
And so, it's it's it's like you're still
there. You're still a sinner. And maybe
you're still you decide that you're
repentant, but something about the fact
that you've gone through this transition
from material life to, you know,
immaterial existence. Suddenly,
forgiveness is just no longer on offer.
It's like the door just slams. This this
generosity, this beauty, this grace, it
just vanishes. And especially when you
consider the fact I mean suppose that I
next week
I'm going to have a religious
conversion. I'm going to have some kind
of conversation. Perhaps this
conversation maybe you're going to say
something at the end of this
conversation. I'm going to going to go
home. I'm going to think, you know what,
they were right and I'm going to convert
to Christianity and I'm going to repent
of my sins and I'm going to be entered
into the kingdom of God. But you
presumably also believe that humans have
libertarian free will. That's one of the
reasons why evil exists in the first
place is that people are free to do what
they like and God cannot control them.
which means that any one of our crew
here could walk over right now, take a
big blunt object, whack me over the
head, and murder me. If they were to do
that right now, I would not go to the
kingdom of heaven.
And yet, if they hadn't done that and an
hour later somebody had done it instead,
then I get into heaven. And that's just
because of somebody else's decision to
do it now rather than later. Right? In
other words, the person who dictates
there whether I get to go to heaven or I
have to go to hell is not God. It's not
me. It seemingly is the person who
decides whether or not to whack me over
the head with a blunt object.
Now, they're they're going to address
that in a second, but I want to address
it first. But yes, first of all, we have
absolutely no authority to send anyone
to heaven or hell. Like anything we do,
the action we do, the murder that he's
talking about that happens from from a
coworker to him, that action doesn't
have anything to do with Jesus saying,
"Well, you shouldn't have got murdered
before you repented."
That action has nothing to do with it.
It is all about the life living leave
living up to it. And so, again, kind of
a an interesting flawed question. And I
think that what Cliff and his son, I
can't remember his name, but what they
need to do here is they truly need to
slow down and really get to the root of
his questions because I feel like
they're trying to give him answers for
questions that are flawed. And so I I
don't think that these are are being
handled well. But let's let's hear what
he has to continue to say cuz I kind of
stopped it a little early. No,
>> it seems almost arbitrary. I mean, death
is very significant for an atheist, but
for a Christian, death is just one thing
that happens to you. It seems very
arbitrary that this beautiful story of
forgiveness and grace and charity and
beauty just stops when you die.
Especially when you consider that your
death is out of your hands. You don't
get to choose when that happens. And
somebody else can bring that on
prematurely for you. And it doesn't
matter what you would have done in the
future. Now you're condemned to an
eternity in hell. If the universe was
religiously ambiguous, I think you'd
have a point because God has made his ev
his his existence so clear because Jesus
has communicated his love so clearly and
so deeply.
We don't have an a good excuse for
rejecting him right now.
>> And yet it's still the case. I mean
maybe well okay maybe yeah I I deserve
to go to hell because I've rejected
Christ. But the message of Christianity
is that everybody deserves to go to
hell. Even those who've accepted Jesus,
they just repent and they accept the
grace. Right. Mhm.
>> But it does doesn't it doesn't it seem a
bit arbitrary that like if I accept that
grace 5 minutes from now I get to go to
heaven and let's say that that is set in
like that's what I'm going to do in 5
minutes I'm going to repent. I just
literally haven't had the time to think
about it because I'm I'm too busy
thinking about the words that are coming
out of my mouth in this particular
sentence. But the very next bit of
mental energy will be spent on
repenting. And yet just before I get
there someone comes and kills me. Well
now I go to hell. May maybe I deserve to
go to hell. that I deserve to go to hell
5 minutes later and 10 minutes later
anyway. It's just that because I didn't
get killed by that random person, just
as chance would have it, I've managed to
get to a point of repentance and now I
get to go to heaven. Aren't Aren't you
seeing here what you're setting up?
You're setting up Hinduism, secularism,
atheism, all the other religions here on
one side because I'm hearing deserved
language. I'm hearing if I don't repent
language. So, it's all about up to me.
If I do this, that and the other, then
don't I deserve to go to heaven? And if
I don't do it, don't I deserve to go to
hell? Versus the Christian faith is the
only faith that says it actually has
nothing to do with you deserving
anything because you cannot deserve it
on your you. God owes us nothing and we
cannot create ourselves and we cannot
give ourselves eternal life. Yeah. It
has to be something from the outside
that we are saying there's nothing like
AA talks about there's nothing in and of
myself that I can do to save myself from
this alcoholism. It has to be God. And
so my whole point would be I don't think
with a Jeffrey Dmer first off I think
he's probably seared his conscience. The
exposure I've had with inmates usually
that type is totally seared their
conscience. It takes a while for them to
come to know Christ and have radical
change. Which is why I think part of the
death penalty is so sad because some
who've changed after 15 years who are
genuine life changers now they're gonna
get put to death.
>> For me though, it gets at the character
of Christ and that this whole Christian
thing
>> is just a matter of the heart.
>> And I think you know that you have a
self, that you have a heart. And I think
you know you are attracted to beauty.
And I think you know that the narrative
that you are most attracted to and so
are all Europeans and Americans and how
the Christian faith is spread all over
the world. how it's not remained in just
one spot says something about how
worldwide we find the beauty in good
triumphing over evil out of there being
a protagonist and antagonist and how
ultimately the leader of the entire
story is the best most beautiful person
imaginable who actually sacrifices for
us even Harry Potter who Christians hate
Harry Potter
>> but even Harry Potter is fully Christian
in every kind of way
>> and so For me, that's the whole piece. I
think you need to look at Doseski and
I'm sure you have Dosteski's life when
he became a Christian.
>> I I believe that the longest road, like
everybody says, is from the head to the
heart. And that was the longest road
definitely for Dostki. He's probably the
best author ever. And he walked in
randomly to a church one day and he
looked at a cross for 4 hours straight
and all of a sudden this understanding
of love and forgiveness. And it wasn't
up to whether I converted, repentant,
was repentant one minute before I died
or anything like that. It was fully God
dying on the cross for me. And he could
not resist that beauty and that's why he
became a Christian.
>> Also ask you went on to write to a
friend.
What in the world? All right, that
answer. I'm sorry to people who like
have questions and then like your
Christian friends answer like that
because honestly I don't even remember
what the question was because with his
answer he went all over the place. But I
I mean I I feel like he was still kind
of getting at this, but the but the the
forgiveness and stuff ends at life or at
death and trying to understand this like
someone being able to like if I was to
repent. Oh, that's right. If I was if I
was going to be like repenting 1 minute
later, 5 minutes later, 10 minutes
later, then wouldn't like like I I I
would go to hell if the person decided
to murder me, but if you murdered me 10
minutes later, then I'd go to heaven.
And I guess maybe at the end of the the
rant he was trying to get to which which
I do agree with a little bit is it's
just so hard because that was so
confusing but is this idea that
we we truly don't deserve anything. I
love that he he said that there is stuff
for us to do. I think he actually
contradicted himself. He contradicted
his dad a little bit here. But there is
things that we need to do and have to do
in ways that were were put into place
for us. Um that God wants us to be in
full communion with us. But I do believe
that God seeks us out, but it is our
responsibility to respond to that
message. So again, I'm sorry if if your
friends answer questions like that
because again, like I even felt like
when he put his finger like this, he was
trying to figure out where he was going
with that. Um, very confusing. So let me
know what you thought about that answer.
I I I got confused during that whole
thing.
>> If I discovered that all of the facts
lay outside of Christ, I would sooner
throw myself in with Christ and reject
the facts and throw myself in with the
facts and reject Christ. And I suppose
depending on who you're talking to, that
can either be a cardinal virtue or a
cardinal vice. Um, I I understand what
you're saying, but of course I'm I'm
imagining, okay, now I'm the killer,
right? And suppose that I know, so
suppose there's like a friend of mine
who's very impressionable and I know
that he's going to go to church next
week. He's been invited and I just know
that he's going to be talked into it. I
know that he's he's going to think this
makes sense. He's right on the brink.
That's all he needs and he's going to
convert to Christianity. So, I decide to
kill him because I'm a malicious person,
you know, and I decide to kill him now
specifically because I know that if I
kill him now, he's going to go to hell.
Whereas, if I kill him next week, he's
going to go to heaven. So, I kill him
today knowing that he hasn't repented
yet so that I can send him to hell. Can
I really believe that I live in a
theological universe where I have that
power? I have the ability to dictate
that he goes to hell instead of heaven
because I've made that decision to kill
him and I've done it on purpose. I find
it difficult to believe that a good God
would oversee that kind of possibility
at all. And some people say to me, well,
that's because God knows that he was
going to repent. And that's what it is
is like, of course, yeah, you're killing
him prematurely, but God knows that he
would have repented next week and
therefore, you know, he still gets to go
to heaven because God knows what would
have happened. You know, in that case,
what's the point in this veil of tears
in the first place? If God knows what
you're going to do anyway, what's the
point in the life? What's the point in
the test? What's the point in the
freedom? Right? But like framed in those
terms, I I I'm not even sure exactly
what the problem is that I'm putting
forward. I I couldn't quite put it into
like a a syllogism, but you understand
the the criticism I'm making here of
this of this picture that it seems like
I have this power
>> to send somebody to hell.
>> Mhm.
>> Right now.
>> Instead of heaven and I get to make that
decision on their behalf. That seems
>> crazy.
>> You bet it is. Cuz you don't. You don't
have the ability to send anybody to
heaven. You don't have the ability to
send anybody to hell
>> because look at the scenario you're
setting up. You're setting up I know
that if he goes to church, he's going to
accept Christ. So, I'm going to kill him
before he goes to church. You don't know
that.
>> Mhm. You don't know who's going to
accept Christ and who's not going to
accept Christ. That's a decision between
them and Christ. Secondly, God is all
knowing. God is fair. God is good. And I
think that's really what this issue gets
down to. Is God fair? Is God going to
judge justly? or is God going to rip
somebody off because they got killed
before murdered before they went to
church? And the answer to that is no.
Nobody's going to hell because they got
murdered before they went to church.
Nobody.
>> So that's the bold statement I was
talking about. I I I would never say
that. Um only because there are so many
different scenarios. Um but there
there's hope that is what we should
have. I don't think we should speak that
boldly, but what we want to do is have
hope that people that die before before
maybe on the on the surface like on what
we see, we we think that they maybe
haven't repented yet. Maybe they aren't
living their lives as a as a Christian
at that time, but we don't know their
hearts. And I I saw someone ask and I
was I was you probably saw me trying to
reach forward. I was trying to find it
on Catholic Answers. Um, but they talked
about this idea that if I'm driving to
go to confession or if I'm just driving
and I'm thinking about, man, I really
need to go to confession, but then I'm
in a car wreck and I die, what are those
chances that I'm able to still make it
to heaven? And they put in there like a
a lot of language that is very kind of
ambiguous because
we can have so much hope in the fact
that your heart was in such a great
place, especially if you're heading to
confession. If you're thinking, I should
probably go to confession and not making
plans for it, that's still like your
heart's in a good place. Um, your
heart's in this place of wanting to
repent and everything. But this is why
at the end of the day, it is so
important to have the magisterium, to
have the church, to have these these
sets, these sacraments that are able to
help us stay in the state of grace.
Because just like I said, we're in this
season of Advent and we're waiting for
the second coming of Christ. And we
don't know if that'll happen here at the
end of this episode. Maybe it'll happen
during this episode or if it's going to
happen 2,000 years after I die. We don't
know. So, we should be preparing every
day as if we were going to to to die
today. And there was a quote I I cannot
remember and I was looking for that too,
but there's a quote that is something
something like um live like you're going
to die today. pray like you're gonna
live forever or some something like
that. And I may have botched that
completely. You guys can comment if if I
completely botched that, but but it's
very true of of this like live like it's
your last day on earth. And in a
Christian and a Catholic especially
standpoint, that would be making sure
that we're doing a good examination of
conscience at the end of each week, at
least at the end of each day. some
people do. Um, and and that we are
taking our mortal sins to confession and
that we are really trying to get
ourselves prepared for that coming of
Jesus. He'd think about all the the
apostles and stuff that he told that
like that he would be coming back and
and [snorts] in in revelation just
realizing like this is how the world
would like how this would all come come
to end and waiting for that and they
didn't see in their lifetime. We might
not see it in our lifetime. I know a lot
of people think we're in the end times
now, but we should be prepared like we
are, but be skeptical of some of the
people online. Um, but that was a bold
statement. That's a bold statement to
say that nobody will go to hell for
whatever he said. He repeats it, I
think, right here.
>> Cuz God is all knowing. He's fair and
he's just.
>> Absolutely.
>> Even if I went back in time in a time
machine, I know
>> I know that this person has repented.
>> You can't go back in a time machine.
>> Yeah, I think that's also probably true.
So that is the interview and know
there's a that's a shorter clip of a
full interview but that's like that
section and like I said that's just such
an interesting question to tackle. I
would give them like a B minus on that.
I think they always present themselves
really well. You know what I love about
the Nectals because I'm not here to like
just bash on them but you know what I
love about the Nectals is I love that
they're willing to go. They're willing
to be on mission. They're willing to
have those conversations. They're
willing to go on one of the top atheist
podcasts and talk about Jesus and be a
witness. And I love that so much. So, I
give so much kudos to them. I really
hope that they keep an open mind and
continue to seek the truth. I know that
they probably have a great prayer life.
I hope that it's deep and rich and not
surface level because they could really
be someone that are making hu they are
making huge impact but man if they were
ones that ever converted to Catholicism
they would make huge impact because they
are not afraid to go have those
conversations and so so kudos to them
but also kudos to Alex who is taking all
of this very seriously. This atheist
probably talks about Jesus more than
most of the No, no, I will say all of
the Christians I know. I mean, he does
it for a living. He's literally, if you
go watch his podcast, he typically he he
talks to some atheists, but he typically
talks to other Christians. Um, he he has
a good relationship with Trent Horn. And
I would really encourage you go guys to
go watch those episodes. And he is
seeking the truth. He doesn't believe
that Christianity is the truth, but he's
seeking the truth. Now, if Alex O'Connor
converted, like I said, there's rumors.
I I would never believe the rumors until
it actually happened until I heard Alex
Okconor say it. But maybe we'll watch
that video next, the one where he it's
it's on his page and it says something
like like, "Did I convert to
Christianity or or something?" But kudos
to him because if he ever converted and
became Catholic, he would he could I
won't say would he could go on to be a
saint. That would be wild. He would be
like a modernday
like Paul going from persecuting
Christians to converting Christians and
that would be super cool. So continue to
pray for Alex and his his channel and
his endeavors. Continue to pray for all
the viewers on that show that they may
also see the light of Christ and the
people that are on on there. Pray for
the Nectals who continue to do God's
work and we we love to encourage them to
continue. Obviously, it's not one of
those like they're not Catholic. I wish
they would stop. Like, no. Like, we need
more people like them. I love that they
are willing to go on this show. If I
ever got asked and invited to be on that
show, I would do it only because Alex
Okcon Oconor is one of my favorite
people to listen to cuz his brain and
how it works and his thinking is so
intriguing and I feel like he would be
so easy to have deep, rich conversations
with, but I would be nervous to be out
there and like, am I ready to be a
witness? It's kind of that same
preparation. Am I ready for the end
times? But am I ready for that next
person that is going to ask me about
Jesus? Am I ready to be a witness? And
so I hope that encourages you and I hope
this video gives you guys hope as we are
in our first week of Advent. I hope you
guys have taken on something. Now it's
not Lint, but Advent's always a great
season that you could take on a new
practice. Whether it's doing the rosary
um once a week, once a day, whatever is
whatever's uh a little bit added for
you. Maybe it's attending a daily mass
as well as Sunday mass or adding a
little prayer with the family before you
guys go to bed. But taking on a little
practice and then maybe even fasting
from something could be something that
really pulls you in closer to Jesus and
helps keeps your eyes fixated on what
the season actually is. Is this this
waiting for the Lord to come. So I hope
you guys have a blessed rest of your
week. We will catch you guys soon. We
have a couple interviews set up. Um, but
we are waiting to record those and so we
will get you guys hooked up on those as
soon as possible. But, um, yeah, hope
you guys continue to check out the
channel. We have Bible study on Tuesday
as well as, um, obviously this video,
too. We're excited to just continue to
pump out more content for you guys. And
thank you guys for supporting. If you
guys have made it this far and you're
listening to Now, I'm praying an extra
Hail Mary for you as soon as I hit stop
record. And you guys have a yeah,
blessed week.